const e="english",a=200,o=54,t=[{id:1254,question:"What did the author of the book study?",option:{a:"B.Sc (Ed) Mathematics",b:" B.A English Language",c:"B.A Literary Studies",d:"BSc Political Science"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:1,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1255,question:"The book described Talle as a?",option:{a:"The precious child",b:"The quiet one",c:" The friendly child",d:"the holy child"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:2,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1256,question:"Who was Omar's immediate sister? ",option:{a:"Ummi",b:"Omar",c:"Salma",d:"Teemah"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:3,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1257,question:"Ummi's husband wanted to study law but the providence chose that he study _____",option:{a:"commerce",b:"accounting",c:"law",d:"history"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:4,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1258,question:"The full meaning of IPO is ______",option:{a:" Independent Police Officer",b:" International Police Officer",c:"Investigating Police Officer",d:" Investigative Police Officer"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"See page 25",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:5,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1259,question:"What is Ummi's Occupation?",option:{a:"Trader",b:"Teacher",c:"Business woman",d:"Nurse"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:6,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1260,question:"What is Ummi Matric Number?  ",option:{a:"UG0001",b:"UG00001",c:"UG001",d:"UG0011"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"See page 17",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:7,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1261,question:"What is full meaning of EMEC",option:{a:"Examination Malpractice and Ethics Committee",b:"Examining Malpractice and Ethics Committee",c:"Examination Malpractice and Ethics Convention",d:"Examination Management and Ethics Committee"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:8,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1262,question:"What is the full name of Salma?",option:{a:" Salma Mohammed",b:"Salma Johnson",c:"Salma Samuel",d:"Salma Ahmed"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:9,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1263,question:"Who was the narrator of the life changer?",option:{a:"Salma",b:"Ummi",c:"Omar",d:"Bint"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:10,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1264,question:"How old is Bint ?",option:{a:"6 years old",b:"4 years old",c:"5 years old",d:"7 years old"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:11,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1265,question:" What question did Bint ask her teacher?",option:{a:"How to say good morning",b:"How to say what is your name",c:" How to say you're welcome",d:"How to say that's very good"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:12,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1266,question:"Who were the people in the car?",option:{a:"Lawal and Labaran",b:" Habib and Labaran",c:"Lawal and Kabir",d:" Labara and Zarki"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:13,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1267,question:"How much did Habib give Tomiwa personally?",option:{a:"Ten thousand naira",b:"Five Thousand Naira",c:"Thirty thousand naira",d:"Twenty Thousand naira"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:14,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1268,question:"How much did Tomiwa give her roommates?",option:{a:" Five thousand naira",b:"Ten thousand Naira",c:"Fifteen thousand Naira",d:"Twenty thousand naira"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:15,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1269,question:"What was Omar's JAMB exam score?",option:{a:"230",b:"250",c:"220",d:"260"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:16,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1270,question:"What is the full meaning of the acronym EMAL",option:{a:"Examination Malpractice",b:"Examination misconduct",c:"Examination management",d:"Examination Manners"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:17,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1271,question:"Who introduced the snail delicacy?",option:{a:"Salma",b:"Ngozi",c:"Ada",d:"Tomiwa"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:18,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1272,question:`"Nothing happened, My friend didn't feel like giving you her number so she gave you mine instead" Who is the friend?`,option:{a:"Salma",b:"Ada",c:"Tomiwa",d:"Ngozi"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:19,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1273,question:"It might be said that there is some kind of sibling rivalry between",option:{a:"Teemah and Bint",b:"Teemah and Omar",c:"Jamila and Omar",d:"Jamila and Teemah"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:20,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1274,question:"One reason the narrator had the habit of entering her children's room unannounced was because",option:{a:"to monitor their hygiene and tidiness",b:"to monitor their prayer life",c:"to check on their welfare",d:" to keep them studying their books"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:21,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1275,question:"According to the story, one of the following is true",option:{a:"Tomiwa and Ngozi are neighbours",b:"Ada and Salma are course mates",c:" Salma and Tomiwa are rivals",d:"Salma and Tomiwa are roommates"},section:`This question is based on Khadijat Abubakar Jalli's novel, "The Life Changer"`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:22,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1280,question:"Prison",option:{a:"rising",b:"risen",c:"potion",d:"motion"},section:"From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that rhymes with the given word.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"Both words have the same sound at the end of their pronunciation.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:27,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1281,question:"Crate",option:{a:"Great",b:"Mint",c:"Creek",d:"Treat"},section:"From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that rhymes with the given word.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"Both words have the same sound at the end of their pronunciation.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:28,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1282,question:"Phone",option:{a:"frown",b:"grown",c:"gown",d:"brown"},section:"From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that rhymes with the given word.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"Both words have the same sound at the end of their pronunciation.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:29,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1283,question:"Choose the word that has a different stress pattern",option:{a:"embrace",b:"suspect(V)",c:"member",d:"project(V)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"All the other options are stressed on the second syllable except suspend that is stressed on the first syllable.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:30,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1284,question:`Choose the option that has the same consonant sound as the one represented by the letter(s) underlined.

Watch<u>ed</u>`,option:{a:"lived",b:"address",c:"letter",d:"match"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"Both have the /t/ sound.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:31,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1285,question:"John's watch is made of GOLD.",option:{a:"Whose watch is made of gold?",b:"What is made of gold?",c:"Is John's watch made of silver?",d:"Is John's necklace made of gold?"},section:"In each of the following sentences, the word that receives the emphatic stress is written in capital letters. From the options lettered A to D, choose the appropriate answer.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:'When answering emphatic stress questions, the option that does not have the "stressed word" becomes the correct answer.',examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:32,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1286,question:"She WORKS at the hospital.",option:{a:"Who works at the hospital?",b:"Where does she work?",c:"Does she work at the hospital?",d:"What does she do at the hospital?"},section:"In each of the following sentences, the word that receives the emphatic stress is written in capital letters. From the options lettered A to D, choose the appropriate answer.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:'When answering emphatic stress questions, the option that does not have the "stressed word" becomes the correct answer.',examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:33,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1287,question:"Aderonke STATED she had a right to her privacy.",option:{a:" Did Aderonke lament she had a right to her privacy?",b:"Did Omowunmi state she had a right to her privacy?",c:" Did Aderonke state she had a right to his privacy?",d:"Did Aderonke state she had a right to her openness?"},section:"In each of the following sentences, the word that receives the emphatic stress is written in capital letters. From the options lettered A to D, choose the appropriate answer.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:'When answering emphatic stress questions, the option that does not have the "stressed word" becomes the correct answer.',examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:34,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1288,question:`Choose the option that has the same consonant sound as the one represented by the letter(s) underlined.

Na<u>t</u>ional


`,option:{a:"sugar",b:"raise",c:"glass",d:"tree"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"Both have the /ʃ/ sound.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:35,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1289,question:"Identify the word that has the stress on the first syllable",option:{a:"Hotel",b:"Esteem",c:"Police",d:"Table"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"Only table is stressed on the first syllable.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:36,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1290,question:`From the options lettered A-D, choose the option that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the underlined word.

Twice, he was <u>repulsed</u> with heavy losses`,option:{a:"repelled",b:"gratified",c:"irated",d:"shocked"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"Repulsed means to be filled with disgust. The most nearly opposite option is gratified.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:37,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1291,question:"I only visited Chidi. This means that",option:{a:"None of the above",b:"I didn't do anything asides visiting Chidi",c:" I didn't go with anyone to visit Chidi",d:"I visited Chidi and his friends"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"The general rule is adverbs should be placed next to the thing they modify. Here, the adverb is modifying visited .",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:38,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1292,question:"My father is <u>parsimonious</u>",option:{a:"thrifty",b:"ungenerous",c:"frugal",d:"generous"},section:`From the options lettered A-D, choose the option that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the underlined word.
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"Parsimonious means to be very unwilling to spend money or use resources. The nearly opposite word is generous.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:39,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1293,question:"Last Easter was an <u>austere</u> period.",option:{a:"harsh",b:"severe",c:"prosperous",d:"sour"},section:`From the options lettered A-D, choose the option that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the underlined word.
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"Austere stresses absence of warmth, color, or feeling and may apply to rigorous restraint, simplicity, or self-denial. The most nearest in meaning is prosperous.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:40,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1294,question:"Choose the word that has a different stress pattern",option:{a:"Project(V)",b:"Basic",c:"Suspect(V)",d:"Neglect"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"All other options are stressed on the second syllable except basic that is stressed on the first syllable.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:41,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1295,question:`Choose the option that has the same consonant sound as the one represented by the letter(s) underlined.

<u>F</u>oot`,option:{a:"live",b:"vegetable",c:"traffic",d:"of"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"Both words have the /f/ sound. Others have the /v/ sound.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:42,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1296,question:"Choose the option that has a different vowel sound from the others",option:{a:"here",b:"beer",c:"idea",d:"head"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"All options have /ɪə/ except head that has the /e/ sound.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:43,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1297,question:"Choose the option that has a different vowel sound from the others",option:{a:"beach",b:"ski",c:"be",d:"been"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"Only been has the /ɪ/ sound. Others have the /i:/ sound.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:44,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1300,question:"My account with the bank is in the red. This means that my account is",option:{a:"heavy",b:"in danger",c:"overdrawn",d:" written in red ink"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"Self-explanatory.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:47,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1301,question:"Between you and _____, he is a liar.",option:{a:"all of the above",b:"me",c:"i",d:"none of the above"},section:"Fill in the gap with the option that best completes the sentence.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:'Use the pronoun "me" when the person speaking is receiving the action of the verb in some way, either directly or indirectly.',examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:48,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1302,question:"The secretary and treasurer did not do ____ job.",option:{a:"their",b:" all of the above",c:"none of the above",d:"his"},section:"Fill in the gap with the option that best completes the sentence.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:'When two subjects are joined together by "and" but the two subjects refer to only one person or thing, a singular verb should be used.',examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:49,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1303,question:"If James fails his examination, his teachers, his parents, his friends, or I ______ to be blame.",option:{a:"are",b:"is",c:"am",d:"not"},section:"Fill in the gap with the option that best completes the sentence.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"When there is a list of nouns or pronouns at the level of the subject, it is the nearest noun or pronoun to the position of the verb that will determine the choice of the verb.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:50,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1304,question:"I have always found that it is helpful to have a few wise and trusted people to ________ you can turn for information and advice.",option:{a:"whom",b:"who",c:"whose",d:"that"},section:"Fill in the gap with the option that best completes the sentence.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"Whom should be used to refer to the object of a verb or preposition.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:51,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1305,question:"We ought to stay away ______ the robbers come back",option:{a:"provided",b:"should in case",c:"although",d:"in case"},section:"Fill in the gap with the option that best completes the sentence.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"When you go to a meeting, or to your workplace you are on business, similarly if you go on an overseas trip for work you are on business.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:52,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1306,question:"It was _____ who killed the goat.",option:{a:"his",b:"him",c:"he",d:"us"},section:"Fill in the gap with the option that best completes the sentence.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"He is used to replace the male subject(performer of action) of the sentence: it functions as a subject pronoun.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:53,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1307,question:"Bankole is upset as his wife does not understand his <u>predicament</u> .",option:{a:"sadness",b:"dilemma",c:"deadlock",d:"happiness"},section:`From the options lettered A-D, choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the underlined word.
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"Both words mean a situation in which a difficult choice has to be made between two different things you could do.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:54,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1308,question:"It is wise not to depend on <u>mundane</u> things.",option:{a:"imported",b:"material",c:"attractive",d:"expensive"},section:`From the options lettered A-D, choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the underlined word.
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"Both means things that are of this earthly world rather than a heavenly or spiritual one.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:55,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1309,question:"Now that the company is <u>insolvent</u> , it will shut down.",option:{a:"overworked",b:"unstable",c:"bankrupt",d:"affluent"},section:`From the options lettered A-D, choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the underlined word.
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"Both mean to be unable to pay what you owe because you do not have enough money.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:56,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1310,question:`Choose the option that has the same consonant sound as the one represented by the letter(s) underlined.

Mo<u>th</u>er`,option:{a:"think",b:"teacher",c:"breathe",d:"watched"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"Both words have the /ð/ sound.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:57,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1311,question:"Pick out the option with a different rhyme",option:{a:"Roar",b:"Four",c:"Growl",d:"Bore"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"Only Growl has a different rhyme",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:58,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1312,question:`Choose the word that has the same rhyme

Watch`,option:{a:"none of the above",b:"botch",c:"catch",d:"match"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"Both words have the same rhyme.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:59,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:1313,question:`Choose the option that has the same stress pattern as the given word.

Student`,option:{a:"Refuse(N)",b:"Propose",c:"Rebel(V)",d:"Superb"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"Refuse(N) and student are both stressed on the first syllable unlike other options stressed on the second syllable.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2022",questionNub:60,hasPassage:0,category:"others"}],s={subject:e,status:200,total:54,data:t};export{t as data,s as default,a as status,e as subject,o as total};
